Well, first congratulations on an
unbelievable career and we're all so
happy for you and also heartbroken that
you won't be around as much, but what
are the emotions for you actually
getting up there to the podium to say
those words out loud? How did it feel
compared to what you thought? Oh, man,
it was different. Um
like I'm always on the top of my head
with stuff, you know, so I just come
just let it come as it go, but I had to
just
let uh let everybody know what I what I
what I'll be feeling from the heart, you
know what I'm saying? Like what gives me
up in the morning, what's what drives
me, what motivates me.
And, you know, I was able to get the
words out, you know, um but um it
definitely was a a different feeling,
you know what I'm saying? It's obviously
a different
atmosphere for me, you know what I'm
saying? Just looking at all my peers and
people who I work with, some people who
I barely work with, who I really don't
see as much, but the support to see them
coming out and supporting was uh was
incredible to see. And, you know, I was
just able to like for them to like see
me express myself when most people
don't, so it definitely was um
uh
a thing of emotions, but uh I was able
to get through it and um I mean
everybody you know said I did a great
job, so cool with it.
I know that for athletes deciding when
to hang it up is so hard and especially
someone like you who can still do it.
What were the factors that made you say,
all right, this is the time? And how
hard was that decision to come to? Yeah,
I mean, it was tough. Obviously, I I'm
I'm very indecisive, so I go back and
forth with everything all the time. Not
on the field. Yeah,
>> [laughter]
>> yeah, not on the field, but uh it was
just one time I just, you know, just
looked myself in the mirror and asked
myself, what do you want to do? You
know, I just kind of like
like asking advice from everybody,
getting different, you know, opinions
and stuff like that and then, you know,
I take all that in and then I just ask
myself, what do you want to do? What do
Lavonte want to do?
Cuz most of the time, you know, in this
life I'm like I like I said, man, like I
put people's feelings above my own a
lot. So, this is the time like this is
my career, this is my my life, so I just
need to figure out what do I want to do.
And I came to the conclusion that you
know, I think well, it's time for me to
give the game up.
Uh obviously, it was it was tough, you
know, talking to Jason and Coach Bowles
is probably one of the toughest
conversations for me to have because how
much, you know, football meant to me,
but at the same time to be able to do it
in this manner, not to be forced out, be
able to do it on my own terms and be
able to play for an organization my
whole career, um what better way to go
out, you know? So, uh
and I just always thought like, you
know, what's what's left, you know,
what's left for me to give, you know
what I'm saying? I never wanted to be
the guy to be, you know, carried off the
field and stuff like that, you know, God
has blessed me to be able to have a
pretty
healthy career, I would say. So, uh
definitely uh
was an amazing journey, but um it it was
just it was just, you know, time for me
to go and just continue and just be a
fan of the game from afar and, you know,
spend time with my family.
You mentioned the conversation with
Coach Bowles. We got to hear him speak
about you in front of the staff in a
very moving speech he gave and I know
you had to have conversations with him
privately. What are the things that he
said to you about you and what that
meant to you based on your relationship
with him?
>> Yeah, man, for him to say, you know, he
he viewed me as one of the best players
he coached, one of the best people that
he've known and, you know, how our
relationship grew from a player-coach
relationship to actual relationship, you
know what I'm saying? And uh and that's
what I talked about, man, like like it
it never was really player-coach like I,
you know, his sons, I know his sons was
playing football, so I used to check up
on him about his sons, he used to check
up on me and stuff like that, like he
used to always used to talk about, you
know, where we going to live at, you
know, he got his house in North
Carolina, like it always was a
conversation like it is
started with football, then it just
evolved into, you know, something
different, so that's when I knew like we
had a really cool, you know, really
cool, close relationship and um you
know, that's a relationship you want to
have with any coach, you know what I'm
saying? And for him to
get up there and say those words, man,
you know, Coach Bowles is a man of
few words, so for him to say all that
stuff about me
was um
was incredible to see, man, it just goes
to show, man, the respect that we have
for each other.
And, you know, that guy, you know, he
always when I first, you know, with
those conversations he always says his
door is open for me, his phone is open
for me, every time I text him he
answers, when I call he answers.
Uh when I need to talk to him and, you
know, about football stuff, he answers,
so uh
he's a
a great man, he's a great mind to be
around and um
uh he's a great great leader of men,
that's something that I really respect
about him.
I've always loved listening to you and
Derrick Brooks talk about each other as
well and just the two most incredible
two of the most incredible players this
franchise has ever known. To finish tied
in tackles, first of all, it sounds like
a dang Disney movie, like
you even if you were trying to do that,
that'd be hard to do. What did that mean
to you and knowing what everybody had
always said about him and to think back
to early in your career and learning
about him, if you'd known you could have
finished with the same number of tackles
as him?
>> Never would have thought. Never would
have thought I'd be in this position.
The day I got drafted and people were
still comparing me to him, like, oh, we
got our next Brooks, but I'm like, hey,
pump your brakes, man. Like, do you guys
understand what this guy has done in
this league and for this community? Uh
but for me to be able to, you know, be
mentioned in the same breath as him is
incredible.
Um you know, obviously, people wanted me
to come back and play another season to
break the record, but at the end of the
day that stuff never, you know, cared to
me, you know what I'm saying? I played
the game for the love of it, not for
what came what comes with it and I think
that's what got me here to where I'm at
today.
have this successful career some people
may say I had today just because, you
know, I did it the right way, you know,
I played the game the right way and I
was playing the game for the right
reasons and everything else God rewarded
me
after. So, that's what I'm thankful for.
And
you know, DB supported me the whole way
through, you know, DB was one of the
first people who I went to lunch with
when I was here,
you know, um even though he made me pay
for the tab, but you know, that's my my
first rookie hazing moment, but you
know, through it through, man, DB always
he was there when I needed him, was
always there when I needed to talk to
him and um that's something I greatly
appreciate about him and uh he texted me
before we got here telling me
congratulations and stuff like that, so
um for me to be tied with him, you know,
I don't
I got something to brag about. When
people
say Derrick Brooks, you got to say my
name, so I'm I'm thankful for that.
And if you're going to brag to your
daughter someday when you're doing the
back in my day,
[laughter and clears throat]
when you're reliving those glory
moments, what do you think those things
are going to be? You want her to know,
you want other people to know, what are
you going to most reminisce on about
your career?
Uh shush.
The most thing I'm reminiscing on, man,
is the friendships I created through
this game, you know, a lot of guys, you
know, as you can see at the press
conference came out to support and
that's something that I love, man, I
built relationships with guys beyond
football. And that's something that I,
you know, kind of always want to do.
Like I said, man, people come from all
walks of life, people come from all
different type of journeys.
And, you know, for us to be able to,
you know, uh
connect and, you know, take our
relationship beyond football is, you
know, incredible, you know, and that's
what this game does, too, you know, uh
bring people from all different walks of
life and be able to collaborate with
each other and
go from there. And, you know,
whenever, you know, she asked me that
question, that's something I would say,
I'm like, yeah, your baby girl, your
your dad was a great person, you know,
and that's what I want her to know.
And she'll definitely know that, I'm
sure, if anybody [laughter] else is
going to talk to her as well, that's
what we'd all say and, you know, I I
know everybody's asked you things about
what you're going to miss the most and
of course, you know, it's the guys, the
relationships. I want to hear what
you're not going to miss. Give me
something that you're not going to miss
when you're done.
Training camp.
>> [laughter]
>> Those long meetings.
Uh
taking on big old offensive linemen all
day.
Man.
Uh
that's that's probably
about it, you know what I'm saying? Just
those those Wednesday practices and
meetings and stuff like that and then
just the training camps and, you know,
actually having to
you know, take a deep breath and go
ahead and hit these big boys cuz you
have to, you know what I'm saying? Like
that stuff is, you know, that stuff is
something that well, I don't care too
much about, you know what I'm saying?
So,
I remember just watching the playoffs
and I'm like seeing people, you know,
you know, watching Seattle play and
watching um
San Fran play, how those guys were just
physical and, you know, running through
people, I'm like, oh, I do that for a
living?
I Yeah, yeah,
I look like that.
Like, man, like that's crazy, that's so
that stuff that I'm, you know, not going
to miss, you know, just dealing with the
the nagging injuries and stuff like
that, man, like
you can miss me with that, I'm I'm I'm
okay, I I got through with these 14
seasons, I'm I'm I'm I'm stamped, I'm
going to stick with that. I think
there's a fair number of running backs
who have retired have said, I won't miss
getting hit by Lavonte David, [laughter]
so you you gave as well as you got,
that's for sure.
How about I think back to you brought up
community college
and thinking you might quit at some
point, that you're trying to give up.
>> Right. If that Lavonte could see today,
what do you think he would think?
Oh, man,
I think that Lavonte would be extremely
proud of this Lavonte now because that
Lavonte right there had a different
mentality. That Lavonte wasn't
you know, was ready to give in too much,
you know, it wasn't didn't didn't care
about, you know, what it took to be
great, you know. And, you know, this
Lavonte
is
definitely
I I I learned a huge a big lesson from
that. You know, uh I actually did quit,
but I was, you know,
talked to talked into, you know, staying
um by my parents, so, you know, I just
had to
click into a different mentality, you
know, and uh
that mentality got me to where I'm at
right now today.
Just uh
go out there and get it. Go out there
and grind and, you know,
be the baddest MF you could be, you
know? And, you know, that's what I
that's what I wanted to become. And that
Lavonte can look at it. This Lavonte now
I'm sure, pretty positive
he'll be definitely motivated to be
where I'm at today.
What would your message be to the Glazer
family?
>> Mhm.
For now what it has been your entire
career getting to be a Buccaneer. What
would you want to say to them? Honestly,
man, I want to thank them, you know, uh
they
they did things they didn't have to do.
You know what I'm saying? Like, it
didn't feel like the relationship
between me and them didn't feel like a
business relationship. It was all gen-
genuine and and love and
giving a player what he's due. And
that's something that I really, you
know, respect about them, you know, um
they communicative with me, you know, uh
they spoke to me every time. Sometimes
you'll get owners who speak to their
players, you know, they speak to you
and, you know, that's something that I,
you know, really respect and I'm sure me
and my family are very thankful for, you
know, they changed our lives. You know,
um changed my life for sure. Helped my
young man from Miami dream come true.
And gave me a lot of
faith and and and and and um
inspiration to give off to the people
who following me. Pay especially people
from my hometown, my home city where I'm
from. Uh to let them know they can do
it. So, uh
um I thank them, you know, so much all
all the time. Every time I got I got I I
give a speech I got to thank them for
sure because not too many people get to
do this. Be able to stick with one
organization for 14 years and, you know,
be able to, you know, go out on their
own terms. And they helped allow me to
do that. So, I'm extremely thankful for
the family. And then finally, what would
you want to say to Bucs fans?
Bucs fans, man, I'm going to miss y'all,
you know, I know it's been a
a tough road since starting in 2012 when
I was here.
Uh to turn around and, you know, be
Super Bowl champions and become a
winning organization.
Uh it was all from the help of you guys,
you know, the motivation, you know, the
the the the the loyalty that you guys
have, the you know, the strict high
standards that you guys have, you know?
Uh I used to see all the messages, you
know what I'm saying? Like, especially,
you know, with the Derrick Brooks
comparisons, you know what I'm saying?
You guys
put me in that same, you know, put me on
that same pedestal and I hope I made you
guys proud. But uh man, I thank you guys
so much, man. You guys were
the reason why I love playing at Raymond
James Stadium. And you guys
get me going, you know, get me going and
get me going all the time, you know what
I'm saying? That's why every time you
know I blow you guys kisses when I'm
coming out the tunnel because
I won't be who I am because uh if it
wasn't for you guys, so I'm extremely
thankful for you.
Well, I think I speak on behalf of all
the Bucs fans when we all say thank you
for all the memories, all of the on and
off the field ways you set a good
example for a bunch of generations to
come. So, we're all going to miss you,
but excited for you and well-deserved
retirement.
>> Appreciate you, Casey. Thank you.